# Nazran Khondokar

Dhaka, Bangladesh

**J** +880-1714-516763 ■ nazran91@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/nazran91 | github.com/NazranKhondokar

## Career Summary

With 5 years of experience Java developer, I've developed many mission-critical projects from scratch to deployment by following Scrum methodology and Java 8/11/17. I have been involved in the development of microservice as an effective team member in EdTech industry. As a software engineer with decent knowledge of SOLID principles, I possess diverse experience in planning & executing multiple projects that solve various business problems and deliver excellent results. I am willing to go the extra mile to overcome any hurdles I may face.

## **Technical Skills**

Languages: Java, JavaScript, TypeScrpt, Dart, Python, XML, C, SQL, Kotlin.

Frameworks & Libraries: Spring Boot, Servlet, Hibernate, Kafka, Angular, Flutter, Android.

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Redis, SQLite, RoomDB, Firestore.

Testing: JUnit. Identity & Access Management: Keycloak. Encryption/Decryption: AES 256. AWS: DynamoDB, EC2, S3.

Build tool: Maven, Gradle. Project management system: JIRA, Open Project, Trello, Asana. Environment: IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, Netbeans, Android Studio, XCode, Eclipse, DBeaver. Operating System: Mac OS, Windows, Linux. Server: Docker, Netflix Eureka, CentOS, Ubuntu.

## Experience

## Ethics Advance Technology Limited

May 2021 - Present

Dhaka, BD

Software Engineer

- Integrated Educational Information Management System | Spring Boot, Kafka, Keycloak, MSSQL, Docker Focused on developing REST API, scaling, analyzing software requirements, and preparing SRS and diagrams. There are 34 modules related to Students, Teachers, and Institutions from Class VI to XII data. I am responsible for developing 4 modules.
- "E-Survey" an annual survey report of 40K institutes:
  - \* Manage to generate circular with date range region-wise to submit institutional data by admin.
  - \* Institute-wise dynamic table generation to submit teacher, student, employee, degree, etc information by the institute head.
  - \* Provide a multi-type admin dashboard to review the institutional data and forward it to the director to finalize data for the survey report.
- "Educational Institute Identification Number" generation:
  - \* Provide the registration panel with valid credentials, the login process, and the application panel to request for "Institute Identification Number" with Govt permission documents.
- "Non-Govt Teacher Registration Certificate Authority" result process and allocation on the institute:
  - \* Build async process to upload certified results from Excel sheet.
  - \* Generate a merit list with an optimized query for all batches.
  - \* Provide a panel to submit subject and designation-wise teacher requisitions from the institute through payment.
  - \* After taking the choice from applicants, generate the result to allocate an applicant through the seat allocation algorithm.

Rokomari Jun 2019 - May 2021

Software Engineer Dhaka, BD

- Rokomari Telemarketing Service: | Spring Web, Security, Data JPA, MySQL, Angular
  Build the service for the telemarketing team where an admin can assign different types of customers to different types of
  agents then agents call customers through the Rokomari telemarketing android VOIP app.
- Rokomari (Android & iOS) | Flutter, Firebase (Crashlytics & Push notification), Facebook SDK, Payment Gateway
  - \* Build a hybrid app that can experience incredible online shopping.
  - \* Build the app architecture with BLoC pattern.
  - \* Build the most complicated product browse page UI, filtering, sorting, and pagination with Restful API integration.
  - \* Build user account section UI & API integration:
    - · User account update, avatar change, phone number & password change with OTP.
    - · User orders, order tracking, product reviews & ratings.

- · Create a favorite list with multi products, delete the list, and create a wish list.
- \* Build authorization section UI & API integration: User registration, login, forgot & change password.
- \* Build the fastest auto-suggestion product search.
- \* Add crashlytics & push notification with Firebase and OneSinal.
- \* Add marketing Facebook SDK & Publish the app to the Apple app store.

#### **UUMOO** Limited

May 2018 - May 2019

Full Stack App Developer

Dhaka, BD

- <u>UUMOO Pocket & Drawer</u> | QR, OCR, AES/RSA, Room DB, Retrofit, Proguard, Google Map clustering
  - \* Build & maintenance a payment service that enables users to exchange, trade and conduct commerce.
  - \* Build the interactive custom UI with XML and Java.
  - \* Working with QR Code, OCR (Firebase ML Kit), android security (AES/RSA).
  - \* Store local data with Room & Load server data with Volley, Retrofit.
  - \* Push data handling and notify the app.
  - \* Detect user location and find available UUMOO at different distances using REST API.
  - \* Custom Google Map with clustering.
  - \* Using ProGuard for obfuscation and making it difficult to reverse engineering

MAX IT

Oct 2017 - Apr 2018

Android Application Developer

Dhaka, BD

- <u>Takshal</u> | Android, Laravel, Facebook auth
  - \* Build & maintain an e-commerce app where users are going to buy the most exclusive Brand watches.

## Infinity Flame Soft

Oct 2016 - Sep 2017

Trainer, Android Application Development

Sylhet, BD

## Education

# Shahjalal University of Science and Technology

Sylhet, BD

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering; CGPA: 3.31 out of 4

Jan. 2013 - Jan. 2018

### Adamjee Cantonment College

Dhaka, BD

Higher Secondary Certificate; GPA: 5 out of 5

Jul. 2010 - Jul. 2012

#### Relevant Coursework

- Data Structures
- Algorithms Analysis
- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning

- Software Development
- Database Management
- Project Management
- Computer Architecture

## **Programming Contest**

- Got a good position on Islamic University of Technology 5th & 6th ICT Fest Programming Contest 2014 & 2015. Also
  on State University National Collegiate Programming Contest 2014.
- 350+ ACM problem solving on <u>Uva</u>, Codeforces.

#### Training

- Training of Trainers (AIUB 2018): Skill Development for Mobile Game and Application
- EATL Mobile App Development Training (SUST 2015): Android Development Course
- Advanced Mobile Game Development & Graphics Design (LICT 2016): Unity3d and Blender Learning
- Bangladesh Android Study Jam (SUST 2015): Udacity Android Development Course

## Language

• Bangla as mother tongue, fluent English